
<concepts>
   <title>Digital Product Management</title>
   <desc>As the field of digital product management continues to rapidly evolve, so do the words and
      phrases used by its practitioners. So we compiled a guide to help navigate the jargon. If you
      hear any that aren’t on this list feel free to leave a comment, but they are probably made
      up</desc>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Agile</prefLabel>
      <definition> Agile product management is based on gathering customer and user feedback on
         prototypes and early product developments, and adapting accordingly. It helps product teams
         reduce waste through iterative work cadences. http://www.agilemanifesto.org </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Scrum</prefLabel>
      <definition> a method within Agile where a development team works together to reach a goal,
         often with physical co-location or close online collaboration of all team members, as well
         as daily face-to-face communication among all team members. There’s hundreds of Agile and
         Scrum tools out there, many of which may sound familiar.
         http://agilescout.com/best-agile-scrum-tools </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Sprint</prefLabel>
      <definition> a cycle of development, often ranging from a week to a month, defined to complete
         a desired milestone </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>User story</prefLabel>
      <definition> a tool used in Agile environments to capture a description of a software feature
         from an end-user perspective. The user story describes the type of user, what they want and
         why. They typically follow a simple template As a type of user, I want some goal so that
         some reason </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>API</prefLabel>
      <definition> Application program interface is a set of routines, protocols, and tools for
         building software applications that defines how components should interact. APIs can extend
         the functionality of your product to third-parties. For example, Uber lets Google bake the
         ability to order a cab right from the Google Maps app. Tim Falls discusses the importance
         of APIs on This is Product Management</definition>
   </concept>
   <category>
      <category-name>UX / Design</category-name>
   </category>

   <concept>
      <prefLabel>VOC</prefLabel>
      <definition> Voice of the customer is a market research technique that produces a detailed set
         of customer wants and needs, organized into a hierarchical structure, and then prioritized
         in terms of relative importance and satisfaction with current alternatives.
         https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voice_of_the_customer </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Design Thinking</prefLabel>
      <definition> a customer-focused, prototype-driven process for innovation. Tim Brown of IDEO
         describes design thinking as “a discipline that uses the designer’s sensibility and methods
         to match people’s needs with what is technologically feasible and what a viable business
         strategy can convert into customer value and market opportunity. </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Mockup</prefLabel>
      <definition> a model or design replica of a product, used to gather user feedback earlier in
         the product lifecycle. Mockups are often produced by designers prior to prototype or
         feature testing</definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Prototype</prefLabel>
      <definition> a simulation of functionality or design meant to put testers in the proper
         mindset to answer questions through behavior rather than self-reporting. Prototypes are the
         means by which experiments generate actionable data and provide a framework by which
         product managers can evaluate and benchmark new product features iteratively. Many tools
         have been developed to make prototyping accessible to product managers.
         http://blog.alpha-ux.co/why-product-teams-need-to-master-rapid-prototyping
         http://blog.alpha-ux.co/a-guide-to-rapid-prototyping-tools-for-product-experiments
      </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>UI</prefLabel>
      <definition> user interface — the visual dimension of any given product or service, as the
         user connects to it. UI designers determine how information and features are laid out
         visually within the greater product. </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>UX</prefLabel>
      <definition> user experience — how a user feels when interfacing with a product. UX designers
         study and evaluate how users feels by looking at such things as ease of use, perception of
         the value of the system, utility, and efficiency in performing tasks. Check out
         uxisnotui.com for a direct comparison of the two.
         http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2010/10/what-is-user-experience-design-overview-tools-and-resources
         http://www.uxisnotui.com/ </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>User Flow</prefLabel>
      <definition> the user’s entire experience from initiating the mockup, prototype, or product to
         closing it and returning to their life. </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Variant / Design Concept</prefLabel>
      <definition> a different version of a product or design, developed in order to see what will
         receive the best response from customers. </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Moderated User Test</prefLabel>
      <definition> a qualitative data gathering session that makes use of live interaction to
         follow-up on outlying responses and paint a fuller picture of the user’s experience using
         the product. Check out Mind The Product for some great user testing tools.
         http://mindtheproduct.com/2015/07/tools-for-customer-feedback/ </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Unmoderated User Test</prefLabel>
      <definition> a user test with no interaction between the test team and the user. Results in
         video clips of the user’s screen, audio recording of the user’s voice, and is often
         tabulated with other user tests to generate quantitative insights </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Observed behavioral data / Self-reported data</prefLabel>
      <definition> Data derived from behavior reflects unconscious or unintentional biases that may
         be excluded when a tester is asked to self-report their experience using a mockup,
         prototype or product
         https://uxmag.com/articles/take-insights-in-stride-using-iterative-experiments-in-product-development
      </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Perception of value</prefLabel>
      <definition> A measure of a tester’s experience viewing a mockup, reflects how the product
         concept translates into value in the user’s mind. </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Net Promoter Score (NPS)</prefLabel>
      <definition> how likely user is to recommend the product to a friend. This is considered to be
         a good indication of how valuable they find the product. </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Split-test &amp; A/B Test</prefLabel>
      <definition> A survey pattern used against large, roughly equal groups of cohorts that
         measures perception of value of two slightly different concepts.
         http://uxmag.com/articles/how-split-testing-validates-new-product-concepts-without-code
      </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Conversion rate</prefLabel>
      <definition> The number of users who achieved a specific goal divided by the total number of
         visitors. Often measured for a specific call-to-action, signup form, or other intended
         goal. </definition>
   </concept>

   <category>Product</category>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Lean</prefLabel>
      <definition> often confused with “cheap,” Lean is a term coined by Eric Ries to describe a
         product development process focused on gathering customer feedback early and often in the
         product lifecycle through customer development and developing a minimum viable product
         https://blog.generalassemb.ly/lean-product-management https://twitter.com/ericries
      </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>GOOB</prefLabel>
      <definition> Get out of the building — Coined by Steve Blank to refer to the process of going
         out and talking to users instead of staying inside speculating about what they want.
         http://www.inc.com/steve-blank/key-to-success-getting-out-of-building.html </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Alpha testing</prefLabel>
      <definition> Typically done toward the end of a development process when the product is in a
         near fully-usable state, to improve the quality of the product and ensure beta readiness.
      </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Beta testing</prefLabel>
      <definition> Typically done just prior to launch, to improve the quality of the product,
         integrate customer input on the complete product, and ensure launch readiness.
      </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Customer Development</prefLabel>
      <definition> not to be confused with sales, marketing, or customer support, customer
         development is the process of gaining customer insights through surveys and in-person
         interviews. http://steveblank.com/category/customer-development-manifesto </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Panelists</prefLabel>
      <definition> A group of people who fit a specific user criteria, used for surveys, interviews,
         and prototype testing. </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Landing page</prefLabel>
      <definition> A single page website, emblematic of a larger product. Landing pages are
         occasionally used to scaffold prototypes or mockups for the sake of providing the user with
         extra context, or to test value propositions before building a product. </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>MVP</prefLabel>
      <definition> minimum viable product — A core component of Lean, an MVP is a stripped down
         version of a product launched quickly in order to gather user feedback earlier in the
         product lifecycle. Large companies are beginning to use “MVEs” instead of MVPs.
         http://blog.alpha-ux.co/making-the-case-for-minimum-viable-experiments </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel> Experiment</prefLabel>
      <definition> A tactic used to quickly gather user insights. Surveys, landing page split tests,
         and interviews are examples of experiments.
         http://blog.alpha-ux.co/making-the-case-for-minimum-viable-experiments </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Stimulus / test criteria</prefLabel>
      <definition> the critical aspect of the experiment the user must view in order to measure
         reaction. If the stimulus or test criteria is buried too deep within the mockup or is too
         hard to find, the user may not know what they are supposed to be reacting to. </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel> CX</prefLabel>
      <definition> customer experience — the interaction between a product and a customer over the
         duration of the relationship. This includes a customer’s attraction, awareness, discovery,
         experience, advocacy and purchase and use. </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>USP</prefLabel>
      <definition> unique selling proposition — the main reason why a user chooses one product over
         another.","markups" https://blog.kissmetrics.com/unique-selling-proposition </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Value prop</prefLabel>
      <definition> short for value proposition, this term describes the user’s primary motivation
         for using the product or the main benefit they receive from it. </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Pivot</prefLabel>
      <definition> People use pivot in so many different contexts I don’t think anyone really knows
         what it is anymore. It originally referred to a small change in a company’s business model
         or product in order to meet customer needs, but now often refers to starting a new product
         all together. </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Incubator</prefLabel>
      <definition> an organization that helps startups and entrepreneurs to grow by providing
         services such as training and office space. </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Innovation lab / skunk works</prefLabel>
      <definition> Typically started within a large company, an innovation lab is a small team of
         employees tasked with building new products and businesses.
         https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skunk_Works </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Disruption</prefLabel>
      <definition> coined by Clayton Christensen, disruption refers to an innovation that gives new
         consumers access to product historically only available to consumers with a lot of money or
         skill often with a new business model. http://www.claytonchristensen.com/key-concepts
      </definition>
   </concept>
   <concept>
      <prefLabel>Unicorn</prefLabel>
      <definition> a startup whose valuation has exceeded (the somewhat arbitrary) $1 billion. Given
         that most startups fail, this term is used to refer to the most successful of the most
         successful startups. </definition>
   </concept>
</concepts>
