<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<concepts>
    <desc>Glossary of Smartlogic terms taken from the site http://smartlogic.com/glossary.
    Used with permission of Ann Kelly.</desc>
<concept>
        <prefLabel>Alternative Label</prefLabel>
        <definition>Alternative labels which are typically synonyms, near synonyms, alternate
            spellings, abbreviations, acronyms, etc. of preferred labels can have 0, 1 or many
            alternative labels per language. Alternate labels are used to drive the
            classification and search experience and so can be any relevant label that helps
            describe the concept.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>API</prefLabel>
        <definition>Application programming interface (API) is an interface implemented by a
            software program which enables it to interact with other software. It facilitates
            interaction between different software programs similar to the way the user
            interface facilitates interaction between humans and computers.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Auto Classification</prefLabel>
        <definition>Auto classification is the process of automatically adding metadata ("tags")
            to an item (a document, article, picture, etc.) to provide a description of that
            item abstracted from the item's content. Classification can involve adding one or
            more metadata values to the item, such as "author", "subject" and "target
            audience". Classification can be done manually, i.e. by reading a document and
            selecting appropriate tags from one or more controlled vocabularies, or the process
            can be automated by a system like Semaphore's .</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Automatic Metadata Tagging</prefLabel>
        <definition>The process of applying Terms or “tags” from a controlled vocabulary (often
            in the form of a taxonomy) to an item of content is known as classification or
            tagging. Tags are stored alongside the item’s content as metadata (data about
            data).The application of these tags can be done manually by a human reading the
            item, referring to the controlled vocabulary and deciding which of the terms is
            appropriate. While this process can be accurate if performed by a subject matter
            expert who is familiar with the controlled vocabulary, when large volumes of content
            need to be indexed this process becomes resource intensive, subjective and may lack
            granularity.   automates the process by encapsulating linguistic evidence in an and
            applying that to content using and . This delivers automatic metadata
            tagging.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Auto Suggest</prefLabel>
        <definition> "reads" a page of content and automatically suggests appropriate terms from
            the client’s taxonomy that can be applied to the metadata.  This process uses
            natural language processing of the text and complex classification routines to
            ensure that the suggestions are consistent and appropriate (and therefore
            valuable).</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Big Data</prefLabel>
        <definition>Big data is a broad term for data sets that are too large or complex for
            traditional data processing methods/applications. Big Data spans three dimensions: ,
            and . These dimensions describe the technologies needed to deal with the issues
            generated by increasing volume (amount of data), velocity (of change), and variety
            (range of data types, sources) of information assets found in organizations.Big data
            has infrastructure requirements for distributed storage, parallel processing, high
            availability and agility. The organizational goal; rapidly analyze the data in real
            or near-real time and use it to drive business decisions.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Big Data Analytics</prefLabel>
        <definition>Big Data analytics is the process of examining large data sets containing a
            variety of data types to reveal patterns, market trends, product information,
            customer preferences and other business information. Increasingly organizations are
            examining their data searching for actionable insights to answer key business
            questions. With the Semaphore platform, organizations can drive effective marketing,
            increase revenue and improve customer service, operational efficiency and risk
            management.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Broader Concept</prefLabel>
        <definition>Broader concepts are concepts that are immediate parents of another concept
            within a hierarchical relationship. For example, in the animal kingdom
            representation an animal is a broader concept than a feline and a feline is a
            broader concept than a house cat.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Business Classification Scheme</prefLabel>
        <definition>Classification, in relation to the Business Classification Scheme (BCS) is
            the systematic identification and arrangement of business activities and/or records
            into categories according to a logical structure or model.A Business Classification
            Scheme is a conceptual model of an organization. There are five common ways of
            arranging groups of items in business classification schemes:Business Classification
            Schemes can be modeled in .</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Business Information Portal</prefLabel>
        <definition>A Business Information Portal is a web portal application that consolidates
            business information into a single application for a specific purpose.The purpose
            could be internally facing – such as a research portal or external facing - such as
            a supplier extranet. Semaphore can be used to create a productized "Business
            Information Portals" for many orgnaizations and sectors.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Business Information Systems</prefLabel>
        <definition>Business Information Systems (BIS) contains the technology that drives
            business. It also relates to the processes, data and the people that use these
            technologies, processes and data every day.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Business Intelligence</prefLabel>
        <definition>Business Intelligence is a technology-driven process for analyzing data and
            presenting actionable information to help corporate executives, business managers
            and other end users make informed decisions.The primary goal of Business
            intelligence software is to extract information from an organization's raw data to
            reveal insights to help a business make faster and more accurate decisions. The
            software typically integrates data from across the enterprise and provides end-users
            with self-service reporting and analysis. BI software uses a number of analytics
            features including statistics, data and text mining and predictive analytics to
            reveal patterns and turn information into insights.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Categorization</prefLabel>
        <definition>Categorization is similar to classification in that it is a process that
            seeks to describe an item by reference to a formal controlled vocabulary such as a
            taxonomy, business classification scheme or file plan. In document management, this
            is normally related to the actual storage of the item (a file can only live in one
            folder) as opposed to classification (where a file can have many metadata
            values).</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Categorization Management</prefLabel>
        <definition>Categorization management involves assigning an agreed category label
            (typically sourced from a Business Classification Scheme or a File Plan) to an item
            for filing. The item can only be assigned to one category. The category often has an
            associated records management process such as a retention or disposal
            schedule.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Classification</prefLabel>
        <definition> is the process of adding metadata ("tags") to an item (a document, article,
            picture, etc.) to provide a description of that item abstracted from the item's
            content.  Classification can involve adding one or more metadata values to the item,
            such as "author", "subject" and "target audience". Classification can be done
            manually, i.e. by reading a document and selecting appropriate tags from one or more
            controlled vocabularies, or the process can be automated by a system like
            .</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Classification Management</prefLabel>
        <definition>Classification management involves assigning agreed labels from a taxonomy
            or ontology to aid subsequent information retrieval. The item can be assigned many
            classification labels if it is about many subjects.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Classification Model</prefLabel>
        <definition>A formal model for sharing knowledge, a classification model is concerned
            with defining topics and placing them in context of a class, with properties and
            relationships to other topics and used to drive the classification of information
            assets.See also: , </definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Cloud Computing</prefLabel>
        <definition>Cloud computing also known as on-demand computing, is a kind of
            internet-based computing, where shared resources and information are provided to
            computers and other devices on-demand. Cloud computing and storage solutions provide
            users and enterprises with various capabilities to store and process their data in
            third-party data centers. It relies on sharing of resources to achieve coherence and
            economies of scale over a network.With Smartlogic’s , your cloud service provider
            manages the content and Semaphore provides and integrated services that apply
            precise and consistent metadata to harmonize information assets, improve search and
            retrieval, drive workflows, secure sensitive information and comply with
            governmental regulations to improve operations and outperform competitors.Semaphore
            Cloud works with all major cloud content management services. Clients can import
            existing corporate and public ontologies, link to external taxonomies, or take
            advantage of starter vocabularies from Smartlogic, including those from WAND, Inc.,
            the premier source for industry, business and specialty domain
            taxonomies.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Concept</prefLabel>
        <definition>Concepts are the units of thought such as ideas, meanings, or (categories
            of) objects and events which underlie many knowledge organization
            systems.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Content Analytics</prefLabel>
        <definition>Content analytics is the act of applying business intelligence (BI) and
            business analytics (BA) practices to digital content. Organizations use content
            analytics software to provide visibility into the amount of content that is being
            created, the nature of that content and how it is used.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Content Classification</prefLabel>
        <definition>Content classification is the process of analyzing a document and adding
            metadata 'tags' that describe that document which are sourced from a taxonomy or
            other form of controlled vocabulary. This can be to:The delivers innovative and
            powerful mechanisms to analyze and classify text by adding 'tags' to text documents,
            web pages or reports that indicate the subject, key dates, people and companies
            mentioned in the content turns masses of unstructured data into usable information.
            The quality of the tags and the speed of processing are essential. Semaphore
            provides this automatic enterprise-grade content classification solution that
            underpins a semantically enhanced system.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Content Classification Routines</prefLabel>
        <definition>Content classification routines are the methods used to classify content.
            Classification routines include:Smartlogic's Semaphore platform uses natural
            language processing and entitiy and fact extraction routines in the classification
            process.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Content Compliance</prefLabel>
        <definition>Content Compliance implies a standard or set of legislation for which
            content is governed. This can be related to its structure – such as compliance to
            Web Accessibility Standards or to the text content meeting certain standards and
            guidelines. routines are used to drive content compliance processes. Rulebases can
            check content for and words or phrases deemed unsuitable and then flag the output.
            Smartlogic also assists in e-discovery routines using accurate content
            classification to ensure that all articles on a subject can be identified and
            extracted.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Content Intelligence</prefLabel>
        <definition> is the combination of semantic technology and information science that
            allows machines to , , , and the content of the enterprise in order to leverage the
            human intelligence locked in that content.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Content Surfacing</prefLabel>
        <definition>Content Surfacing is a way of presenting or previewing content typically
            embedded in links contained in Tweets, RSS feeds, Facebook and other content
            streams. Dynamic web portals use semantic technology for content surfacing on
            demand. For example, a web page that is linked to a Google AdWords advert could be
            automatically rendered on demand, surfacing tagged articles into a defined page
            template. The result is a highly topical page that should increase click
            through.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Contextual Searching</prefLabel>
        <definition>Contextual searching refers to proactively capturing the information needs
            of a user by automatically augmenting the user query with information extracted from
            the search context; for example, by using terms from the web page the user is
            currently browsing or knowledge of previous searches.A number of algorithms are used
            to implement contextual search including:These methods improve the search experience
            by delivering the most relevant content to the user.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Controlled Vocabularies</prefLabel>
        <definition>Controlled vocabularies are carefully selected lists of words and phrases,
            which are used to tag documents or content to improve search and retrieval
            results. These lists of terms are curated within an organization or industry by a
            formal working group. A controlled vocabulary does not necessarily have any
            structure (such as a hierarchy or parent-child relationships).</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Distributed Processing</prefLabel>
        <definition>Distributed processing is a phrase used to refer to a variety of computer
            systems that use more than one computer (or processor) to run an application. A
            distributed system is a software system in which components located on networked
            computers communicate and coordinate their actions by passing messages. The
            components interact with each other in order to achieve a common goal. Three
            significant characteristics of distributed systems are: concurrency of components,
            lack of a global clock, and independent failure of components.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Document Management</prefLabel>
        <definition>The management and control of documents with emphasis on their dynamic and
            transactional nature including indexing and retrieval, revision and version control,
            work flow and information content. This process is normally constructed in a
            Document Management System (DMS) providing features such as Check-In/Check-Out,
            automatic major and minor versioning, Workflow and document routing,
            etc.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Documentum Search</prefLabel>
        <definition>The search engine running against the Documentum Enterprise Content
            Management software. Documentum Search Services in its current release uses the
            Apache Lucene engine and previously the FAST ESP engine, embedded as OEM
            software.Integrating to a product like Documentum required specific effort to ensure
            all the database content is correctly indexed and specifically that Access Control
            Lists (ACLs) are obeyed.  Other search software vendors provide alternative search
            options for Documentum.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Dynamic Navigation</prefLabel>
        <definition>Dynamic navigation allows a navigation menu to update automatically, based
            on the state of a website's content. A website is often structured using a core
            static navigation taxonomy (Home &gt; Products &gt; Product Detail). An ontology,
            containing multiple facets can deliver dynamic navigation.For dynamic navigation, a
            topic page is constructed around a concept (or Term) in the ontology.  From this
            page the user can be presented any number of relationships to other topics, all of
            which are maintained in the ontology.  This abstraction of the relationships to the
            ontology is typically easier to manage and change than hard-coded linking on a
            website.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Enterprise Content Management</prefLabel>
        <definition>Enterprise Content Management (ECM) is the strategies, methods and tools
            used to capture, manage, store, preserve, and deliver content and documents related
            to organizational processes. ECM covers the management of information within the
            entire scope of an enterprise whether that information is in the form of a paper
            document, an electronic file, a database print stream, or even an email. ECM is an
            umbrella term covering document management, web content management, search,
            collaboration, records management, digital asset management (DAM), work-flow
            management, and capture and scanning. ECM is primarily aimed at managing the
            life-cycle of information from initial publication or creation to archival and
            eventually disposal(ref: www.wikipedia.com)</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Enterprise Document Management</prefLabel>
        <definition>Enterprise Document Management (EDM) is a sub-set of Enterprise Content
            Management. The focus of these technologies is the scanning or uploading, routing,
            updating, version control and storage of documents (rather than say the creation and
            publishing of web pages). EDM and eDRMS Enterprise Document Management is often
            linked with Records Management (the ability to declare a document as an item of
            record and manage it according to retention or disposal schedules). The combined
            software is often referred to as an electronic Document and Records Management
            System (eDRMS).</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Enterprise Search</prefLabel>
        <definition>Enterprise search is the practice of making content from multiple sources,
            such as databases and intranets, searchable to a defined audience.Enterprise search
            systems index data and documents from a variety of sources such as: file systems,
            intranets, document management systems, e-mail, and databases. Many enterprise
            search systems integrate structured and unstructured data in their collections.
            Enterprise search systems also use access controls to enforce a security policy on
            their users.The term "enterprise search" is used to describe the application of
            search technology to information within an organization (though the search function
            and its results may still be public). Enterprise search can be contrasted with “web
            search”, which applies search technology to documents on the open web, and “desktop
            search”, which applies search technology to the content on a single computer.Web
            search indexes HTML pages available via a “web crawler”. Enterprise search needs to
            index the multiple content sources, manage aspects such as security levels (ensuring
            the search index does not allow unlimited access to restricted resources) and have
            potentially multiple interfaces to suit different audiences (executive portal, staff
            intranet, supplier extranet, etc.).</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Enterprise Semantic Platform</prefLabel>
        <definition>An enterprise semantic platform is comprised of:</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Entity Extraction</prefLabel>
        <definition>Entity extraction is the natural language processing and algorithmic
            detection of different entity types within a piece of text (people names, city
            names, job titles, etc.). The with an provides entity extraction for over 30 entity
            types.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Entity Identifier Mapping</prefLabel>
        <definition>Entity Identifier Mapping is the process of defining how the same entities
            with different values relate to each other.  For example, “Orange” &lt;is brand
            of&gt; ”France Telecom” &lt;has stock ticker&gt; “FTE”.  This mapping can be used
            via to perform Entity Normalization.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Entity Normalization</prefLabel>
        <definition>The process of tagging content with entities (names, places, etc) created
            from automatic entity extraction routines or manually added (for example
            Organization Name manually added to a financial research piece). Entity
            Normalization is used by companies who want to normalize the different entity values
            against their own standard. For example, a controlled vocabulary managed in a tool
            like might have an agreed label of “British Airways” and the rulebase classification
            process would map any entities (“B.A.”, “ba.com”) found within the content or in
            meta fields to the agreed label.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Faceted Classification System</prefLabel>
        <definition>A faceted classification system is a classification scheme, which is used to
            organize knowledge into a systematic order. Faceted classification systems use
            semantic categories (general or subject-specific) that are combined to create the
            full classification entry. The facets in a faceted classification system could be:A
            faceted classification system can automatically add metadata derived from multiple
            facets.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Faceted Search</prefLabel>
        <definition>Faceted search is a technique for accessing information organized using a
            faceted classification system, which allows users to explore a collection of
            information by applying multiple filters to a result set in order to find the most
            relevant information. How does faceted search work?Facets are the topic areas a user
            might expect to use to further filter and refine the result set. This is most
            obvious on online retail sites where the facets would include brand, size, color,
            etc. For information portals the facets could be Subject, Geography, Author, Format
            or Department.Each Facet will show a list of appropriate terms sourced from a
            controlled vocabulary or taxonomy (and managed in a tool like ). Selecting a term
            should filter the results so a sub-set of the original results are shown. The
            mechanism for filtering varies. At its simplest the facet term is simply added to
            the original search query (free-text results for “users query” AND “filter term”). A
            more powerful filter is available when the content has been accurately tagged
            (manually or by a tool like ). The filter can then be all the items from the
            original result set that have a metadata value of the facet value.Sometimes
            displaying the facets in a hierarchy provides more context. A service like can
            deliver the taxonomy tree information (and indeed drop of nodes where there are no
            matching content items).The level of facet support differs across search platforms.
            Google Search Appliance and Apache Solr provide the basic indexing structures which
            can be populated and used by to deliver a compelling search user
            experience.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>FAST Search</prefLabel>
        <definition>The FAST ESP Enterprise Search software created by Fast Search &amp;
            Transfer ASA (acquired by Microsoft in January 2008), is now provided as “FAST
            Search for SharePoint 2010.”Microsoft FAST Search Server 2010 for SharePoint offers
            a new choice in enterprise search. Combining the power of FAST with the simplicity
            of SharePoint, FAST Search Server 2010 for SharePoint delivers an exceptional
            intranet and people search experience and a platform for building custom
            search-driven applications.Semaphore for Microsoft FAST integrates the Semaphore
            Open Semantic Platform into the indexing and query capabilities of FAST to add true
            “aboutness” taxonomy classification and powerful ontology driven
            navigation.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Federated Search</prefLabel>
        <definition>Federated search is the simultaneous search of multiple online databases or
            web resources (including other search engines). From a single interface, the query
            is distributed to multiple resources and the results combined into a single result
            set with appropriate de-duplication and relevance ranking.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Findability</prefLabel>
        <definition>Findability is a term used to describe the ease with which you can search
            for and find information. Although not exclusive to the World Wide Web it is usually
            used in the context of the internet. Findability pertains to information on the web
            as well as within a particular website.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Google Search Appliance</prefLabel>
        <definition>The (GSA) is the Google search software installed on a rack-mounted server
            that can be rapidly plugged into a data center to provide Enterprise Search
            capabilities. Semaphore for Google Search Appliance integrates the Semaphore Open
            Semantic Platform into the indexing and query capabilities of the GSA to add true
            “aboutness” taxonomy classification, entity extraction for multiple facets and
            powerful ontology driven navigation.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Hierarchical Faceted Search</prefLabel>
        <definition>Hierarchical faceted search describes a system of accessing information
            about a collection of objects, classes or subjects. Content is organized into a
            faceted classification system according to rules derived from concepts found in an
            ontology. This allows it to be ordered by relevancy into a hierarchy that is defined
            by accurately determined subject metadata for use by a search engine.Hierarchical
            faceted search allows users to explore a domain by using ontologies to list and
            subsequently filter out those results that are unwanted or irrelevant, facilitating
            ease of search and ensuring precise, consistent and accurate search
            results.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>HIPAA</prefLabel>
        <definition>HIPAA is the acronym for the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability
            Act that was passed by Congress in 1996. HIPAA was enacted by the United States
            Congress and signed by President Bill Clinton in 1996. It has been known as
            the Kennedy–Kassebaum Act or Kassebaum–Kennedy Act after two of its leading
            sponsors.Learn more about  on Wikipedia.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Indexing Solutions</prefLabel>
        <definition>Indexing content is synonymous with – applying one or more terms from a
            formal indexing structure (taxonomy, ontology, controlled vocabulary or thesauri).
            An indexing solution, such as , automates this process providing a result that is
            scalable and repeatable (unlike manual indexing or other statistical classification
            approaches).</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Information Professional</prefLabel>
        <definition>An information professional deals with the management and organization of
            information and its distribution to information consumers. Job titles may include
            Information Scientist, Librarian, Enterprise Data Architect, and Information
            Architect.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Information Retrieval</prefLabel>
        <definition>Information retrieval (IR) is the science of searching for documents, for
            information within documents, and for metadata about documents, in relational
            databases as well as the World Wide Web.There is overlap in the usage of the terms
            data retrieval, document retrieval, information retrieval, and text retrieval, but
            each also has its own body of literature, theory, praxis, and technologies. IR is
            interdisciplinary, based on computer science, mathematics, library science,
            information science, information architecture, cognitive psychology, linguistics,
            and statistics.  – Wikipedia</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Knowledge Management</prefLabel>
        <definition>Knowledge Management (KM) comprises a range of strategies and practices used
            in an organization to identify, create, represent, distribute, and enable adoption
            of insights and experiences. Such insights and experiences comprise knowledge,
            either embodied in individuals or embedded in organizational processes or practice.
            – WikipediaKnowledge is often defined as “tacit” (that enhanced by experience and
            use) or “explicit” (that which can be formally captured and codified).  Semaphore
            Ontology Editor provides a software tool for capturing explicit
            knowledge.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Linked Open Data</prefLabel>
        <definition>Linked Open Data describes a method of publishing structured data so that it
            can be interlinked and become more useful through semantic queries. It builds upon
            standard Web technologies such as HTTP, RDF and URIs, but rather than using them to
            serve web pages for human readers, it extends them to share information in a way
            that can be read automatically by computers. This enables data from different
            sources to be connected and queried.Tim Berners-Lee, director of the World Wide Web
            Consortium (W3C), coined the term in a design note about the Semantic Web project. -
            Wikipedia</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Metadata Standards</prefLabel>
        <definition>Metadata elements grouped into sets designed for a specific purpose, e.g.,
            for a specific domain or a particular type of information resource, are called
            metadata schemes.For every element the name and the semantics (the meaning of the
            element) are specified. Content rules (how content must be formulated),
            representation rules (e.g., capitalization rules), and allowed element values (e.g.,
            from a controlled vocabulary) can be specified optionally. Some schemes also specify
            in which syntax the elements must be encoded, in contrast to syntax independent
            schemes. Many current schemes use Standards Generalized Mark-up Language (SGML) or
            XML to specify their syntax (NISO, 2004). Metadata schemes that are developed and
            maintained by standard organizations (such as ISO) or organizations that have taken
            on such responsibility (such as the Dublin Core Metadata Initiative) are called
            metadata standards. – Wikipedia</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Metadata Values</prefLabel>
        <definition>Metadata is often defined as “data about data”. It is structured information
            that describes, explains, locates, or otherwise makes it easier to retrieve, use or
            manage an information resource. Example of Metadata Values In the structure there is
            typically an element and a value. For example: &lt;Meta Publisher [element] =
            “Smartlogic” [value]&gt;</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Narrower Concept</prefLabel>
        <definition>A Narrower concepts are immediate children of other concepts, within a
            hierarchical relationship. Narrower concept are more specific than their parents for
            example a house cat is a more specific concept than a feline and feline is a more
            specific concept than an animal.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Natural Language Processing</prefLabel>
        <definition>"Natural Language Processing (NLP) is both a modern computational technology
            and a method of investigating and evaluating claims about human language.Some prefer
            the term Computational Linguistics in order to capture this latter function, but NLP
            is a term that links back into the history of Artificial Intelligence (AI), the
            general study of cognitive function by computational processes, normally with an
            emphasis on the role of knowledge representations, that is to say the need for
            representations of our knowledge of the world in order to understand human language
            with computers.Natural Language Processing (NLP) is the use of computers to process
            written and spoken language for some practical, useful, purpose: to translate
            languages, to get information from the web on text data banks so as to answer
            questions, to carry on conversations with machines."  - Natural Language Processing
            Research Group at the University of Sheffield Department of Computer Scienceemploys
            NLP techniques in order to assess and process text for rule-based .</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Ontology</prefLabel>
        <definition>A formal model for sharing knowledge, an is concerned with defining topics
            and placing them in context of a class, with properties and relationships to other
            topics.More extensive than a taxonomy, an ontology refers to the classes of
            information (or categories) within a domain and the relationships between those
            categories. The relationship must be able to be defined and convey meaning -
            consider it the next stage from a standard "related to" associative relationship in
            a thesauri.One ontology can vary widely from the next ontology, not only when it
            comes to their content, but also in the way that they are implemented and in the
            ontology’s structure. This is why it is possible to build an ontology (or several)
            which specifically fits the needs of your company or organization when it comes to
            managing your information An ontology can be built to understand a particular
            vocabulary set which is unique to your informational needs or industry, known as a
            common language for your ontology. This can be a great asset when using your
            ontology to discover certain industry-relevant information, especially when that
            data is held in different databases, content repositories and systems.An ontology
            defines the properties and attributes of content within your domain. The ontology,
            or semantic model is also able to understand the relationships between different
            pieces of information. The ontology is able to judge the meaning of content rather
            than just its literal values and also the application of this data to the purpose of
            your business or organization. An ontology is perfectly suited to defining
            knowledge, its attributes and its relationships to other content. An Ontology is
            created to understand the logic of its user (which may be abstract when compared to
            usual information management tools) in order to process information semantically.
            This means that the ontology can be used to integrate databases and huge amounts of
            information and content from across different systems. This makes an ontology an
            extremely useful tool in the management and retrieval of your knowledge base and
            content repositories.An Ontology is devised to be rich in defining those semantic
            relationships between pieces of information. This increases the number of possible
            ways in which information can be related, the ontology adding new levels of depth to
            your information searching and queries. An ontology is designed to effectively
            communicate the meaning of the terms which are defined by your application of the
            software and the ontology uses natural language to document these definitions. The
            ontology will be coherent and understandable, whether the definitions are made using
            formal or informal, more human-friendly, language. The ontology will be designed
            specifically for your needs of the application, meaning that the ontology offers a
            range of anticipated tasks and the ability to define new uses as and when you
            require it of your ontology. is a web-based software tool designed to facilitate
            collaboration between users to develop and build ontologies and tailor them for use
            in applications. OE models concepts as Preferred Labels and the hierarchical and
            associative relationships between them provide context and meaning.See also: ,
        </definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Ontology Editor Tool</prefLabel>
        <definition>The Tool is multi-user, web-based software application that supports the
            design, development, testing and maintenance of Knowledge Organizing Systems such as
            , controlled vocabularies and thesauri, etc.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Ontology Software</prefLabel>
        <definition>Ontology software provides a user interface in which to develop an ontology,
            a logic layer that ensures the consistency and accuracy of the information entered
            and an application interface for other programs to interrogate the ontology as
            required. lets users model the concepts, topics, products, market segments, and
            organizational structures that are uniquely important to each organization and
            industry. It gives you the finesse and power of knowledge management industry
            standards, like RDF and SKOS, with the ease of a familiar Web based
            interface.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>OWL Ontologies</prefLabel>
        <definition>The Web Ontology Language (OWL) is a family of knowledge representation
            languages for authoring ontologies for the semantic web. The definition allows a
            great deal of flexibility and granularity in the ontology definition and is
            typically aimed at machine learning and computer inference systems.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Platform as a service (PaaS)</prefLabel>
        <definition>PaaS is a category of cloud computing services that provides a platform for
            customers to develop, run, and manage web applications without the complexity of
            building and maintaining the infrastructure typically associated with developing and
            launching an app. PaaS can be delivered in two ways: as a public cloud service from
            a provider, where the consumer controls software deployment and configuration
            settings, and the provider provides the networks, servers, storage and other
            services to host the consumer's application; or as software installed in private
            data centers or public infrastructure as a service and managed by internal IT
            departments.With , your cloud service provider manages the content and Semaphore
            provides and integrated services that apply precise and consistent metadata to
            harmonize information assets, improve search and retrieval, drive workflows, secure
            sensitive information and comply with governmental regulations to improve
            operations.Semaphore Cloud works with all major cloud content management services.
            Clients can import existing corporate and public ontologies, link to external
            taxonomies, or take advantage of starter vocabularies from , and their
            partners.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Preferred Label</prefLabel>
        <definition>A preferred label is the official name for a concept. Each concept can have
            only one preferred label per language.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Related Concept</prefLabel>
        <definition>A relationship between two concepts within a model (taxonomy, ontology,
            controlled vocabulary, thesauri).  Models can be enriched using relationships
            especially when two concepts are related but not directly linked in a hierarchy.
            supports relationships – the default associative relationship is Related
            Concepts.  </definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Resource Definition Framework (RDF)</prefLabel>
        <definition>The Resource Description Framework (RDF) is a family of World Wide Web
            Consortium (W3C) specifications designed as a metadata data model. It is used as a
            general method for conceptual description or modeling of information that is
            implemented in web resources, using a variety of syntax notations and data
            serialization formats. It is also used in knowledge management
            applications.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Search Accuracy</prefLabel>
        <definition>Search accuracy is an interesting topic that is completely subjective. The
            “right answer” for one person may differ radically for another person running the
            same search over the same content. The level of accuracy is normally discussed along
            two axis – Precision and Recall.Precision relates to the relevance ranking
            algorithms employed by the search engine and tries to answer the question “Are the
            results shown the best ones for this search?” Recall relates to the scope of the
            search and the content indexing and tries to answer the question “Are all the
            possibly useful results returned in this search?” Semantic enhancement
            (classification and tagging of content done intelligently) will raise search
            accuracy having a beneficial impact on both precision and recall.See also
        </definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Self-service</prefLabel>
        <definition>Self-service is a term given to the retrieval of information by a user
            rather than having to contact a third-party to supply the same information. In the
            case of company websites or intranets, self-service is vital to the user experience,
            as well as being the cheapest form of providing information, as information can be
            served again and again to different audiences, without the need for manning call
            centers or responding to emailed enquiries. Well-classified, structured content is
            therefore crucial to an effective self-service model.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Semantic Search</prefLabel>
        <definition>Semantic search seeks to improve search accuracy by understanding searcher
            intent and the contextual meaning of terms as they appear in the search results. A
            number of mechanisms are employed to do this:  for search engines with compatible
            API access (i.e. , ).  provides an integrated end-to end solution using best of
            breed enterprise search and the market leading open semantic platform.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Semantic Search Engine</prefLabel>
        <definition>A search engine that has been extended from providing core capabilities
            (indexing multiple sources, free-text retrieval, relevance ranking) to deliver
            semantic search capabilities. Semantic search engines improve search accuracy by
            attempting to understand searcher intent and the contextual meaning of terms as they
            appear in the result set to generate relevant results.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Semantic Software</prefLabel>
        <definition>Any software that adds additional context and meaning to the language used
            in an application to improve its use and accessibility to human readers and machine
            agents.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Semantic Technologies</prefLabel>
        <definition>Semantic technologies have the capacity to extract meaning from unstructured
            information found within an enterprise and make it available for processing.
            Semantics uses models which define the concepts, topics, products, market segments
            and organizational structures associated with a business domain and fact extraction
            to assign metadata tags so information can be managed, used and
            governed.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Semantic Wave</prefLabel>
        <definition>The mainstream adoption of semantic technologies as seen by the emergence of
            the Semantic Web initiative and the growing adoption of technologies such as the
            Semaphore Open Semantic Platform.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Semantic Web</prefLabel>
        <definition>The Semantic Web is an extension of the Web through standards created by the
            World Wide Web Consortium (W3C). The standards promote common data formats and
            exchange protocols for the Web, most fundamentally the Resource Description
            Framework (RDF).According to the W3C, "The Semantic Web provides a common framework
            that allows data to be shared and reused across application, enterprise, and
            community boundaries.” The term was coined by Tim Berners-Lee for a web of data that
            can be processed by machines. - Wikipedia</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Semaphore Search</prefLabel>
        <definition>Semaphore search is the integration of the with enterprise search engines to
            deliver a robust, scalable semantic search solution that delivers an exceptional
            user experience.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>SharePoint Search</prefLabel>
        <definition>The Enterprise Search solution provided as part of Microsoft’s Enterprise
            Content Management solution SharePoint. The SharePoint (or Microsoft Office
            SharePoint Server [MOSS] 2007) search delivered basic enterprise search
            capabilities. The SharePoint 2010 release greatly enhances the scale and
            functionality for search.Integrating the means content can be automatically
            classified in the SharePoint Library and indexed by SharePoint Search. Semaphore
            Search Web Parts add powerful ontology driven navigation components to the search
            results.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>SharePoint Taxonomies</prefLabel>
        <definition>Microsoft use the word “taxonomy” in relation to SharePoint 2007 and
            SharePoint 2010 to describe SharePoint’s site map structure. Most Information
            Management practitioners think of this as the broader problem of applying terms from
            a formal organizational or industry taxonomy (e.g. Integrated Public Sector
            Vocabulary [IPSV] in UK Government or Medical Subject Headings [MeSH] in Life
            Sciences and Healthcare) to content by adding values to a taxonomy related site
            column.Semaphore enables management of SharePoint taxonomies - SharePoint 2007 and
            SharePoint 2010 have no support for creating and maintaining taxonomies (in the
            sense of a complex hierarchical list), deploying a central taxonomy structure across
            site collections or automatically adding taxonomy values to documents, list items,
            blog entries, etc. Semaphore for SharePoint adds this capability to SharePoint 2007
            and SharePoint 2010 to assist information management and retrieval.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Site Columns</prefLabel>
        <definition>A site column is a SharePoint term to describe a list column, or metadata
            field that can be shared across all libraries and lists in any Site in a Site
            Collection. In our Semaphore solution a “Semaphore Classification” type site column
            adds taxonomy support to SharePoint lists. This is a dynamic column that provides
            powerful taxonomy support to SharePoint users: Items can be manually labelled using
            a taxonomy tree browser; items can be manually labelled using a full text search
            over the taxonomy including the main terms and any synonyms and Items can be
            automatically classified with terms from the taxonomy.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>SKOS</prefLabel>
        <definition>Simple Knowledge Organization System (SKOS) “is an area of work developing
            specifications and standards to support the use of knowledge organization systems
            (KOS) such as thesauri, classification schemes, subject heading systems and
            taxonomies within the framework of the Semantic Web.” – W3C</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Smartlogic Semaphore LTD</prefLabel>
        <definition>Unstructured Data Experts Semaphore is the bridge between human language and
            computersFind value in content and empower business intelligence.You get the power
            of computer processing with the human ability to understand what is in your content.
            We call this content intelligence, and it helps companies worldwide find value in
            content far beyond its first use, discover connections in that content and power
            business-critical tasks at speeds people alone simply cannot achieve.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Solr Search</prefLabel>
        <definition>Solr is the open source Enterprise Search Solution form the Apache Lucene
            project. integrates the Semaphore Open Semantic Platform into the indexing and query
            capabilities of the Solr to add true “aboutness” taxonomy classification, entity
            extraction for multiple facets and powerful ontology driven navigation.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Structured Data</prefLabel>
        <definition>A type of data model that organizes data elements (name, address, city etc.)
            and standardizes how the data elements relate to one another (ie. type, format).
            Structured data is used in relational database systems.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Subject Identification</prefLabel>
        <definition>A structure such as a taxonomy or Business Classification Scheme used to
            identify the subject of an item.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Tagged Information Feeds</prefLabel>
        <definition>Information Feeds deliver content from specific domain in a structure way,
            for example market research from Reuters or news stories from the McClatchy
            newspapers group. This content is typically “meta-tagged”, i.e. classified against
            one or more set vocabularies in order to help: Syndication: When selling the
            content, the producer will define packages that include sets of tags.
            Personalization: When subscribing to content, a user may want to filter their RSS
            feed to a precise set of tags.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Taxonomic Scheme</prefLabel>
        <definition>“Taxonomy is the practice and science of classification. The word finds its
            roots in the Greek τάξις, taxis (meaning 'order' or 'arrangement') and νόμος, nomos
            (meaning 'law' or 'science'). A taxonomy, or taxonomic scheme, is a particular
            classification ("the taxonomy of ..."), arranged in a hierarchical structure.
            Typically this is organized by parent-child relationships.” – Wikipedia</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Taxonomy</prefLabel>
        <definition>A , or taxonomic scheme, is a particular classification ("the taxonomy of
            ...") of topics arranged in a hierarchical structure.   The topics are defined with
            an agreed label or concept.  Information science protocol determines that the
            concepts are ordered hierarchically using a parent-child relationship type referred
            to as "Broader Than/Narrower Than (BT/NT)".“Taxonomy (from Greek taxis meaning
            arrangement or division and nomos meaning law) is the science of classification
            according to a pre-determined system, with the resulting catalog used to provide a
            conceptual framework for discussion, analysis, or information retrieval.The
            development of a good taxonomy takes into account the importance of separating
            elements of a group (taxon) into subgroups (taxa) that are mutually exclusive,
            unambiguous, and taken together, include all possibilities. In practice, a good
            taxonomy should be simple, easy to remember, and easy to use.One of the best known
            taxonomies is the one devised by the Swedish scientist, Carl Linnaeus, whose
            classification for biology is still widely used (with modifications). In web portal
            design, taxonomies are often created to describe categories and subcategories of
            topics found on the Web site. The categorization of words on whatis.com is similar
            to any Web portal taxonomy.” – whatis.comSmartlogic builds and manages taxonomies in
            our tool and uses them for classification and navigation.  The taxonomies we
            typically use are business and industry related, for example the Integrated Public
            Sector Vocabulary – a taxonomy used by UK Government to classify all content shared
            with the public and between departments.See also: , </definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Taxonomy Management</prefLabel>
        <definition>'Taxonomy' derives from Greek 'taxis' (meaning arrangement or division) and
            'nomos' (meaning law). It describes the science of classification according to a
            pre-determined system, with the resulting catalogue used to provide a conceptual
            framework for discussion, analysis, or information retrieval.In theory, the
            development of a good taxonomy takes into account the importance of separating
            elements of a group (taxon) into subgroups (taxa) that are mutually exclusive,
            unambiguous, and taken together, include all possibilities. So, in practice, a good
            taxonomy should be simple, easy to remember, and easy to use. Unfortunately, this is
            not always the case, and where complex taxonomies are involved, taxonomy management
            is necessary. allows any enterprise or organization to build and manage large
            subject taxonomies with powerful, simple to use enterprise software. The provides a
            user interface in which to develop a taxonomy, a logic layer that ensures the
            consistency and accuracy of the information entered (ideally conforming to the ISO
            2788 standard 'Guidelines for the establishment and development of monolingual
            thesauri') and an application interface for other programs to interrogate the
            taxonomy as required.The Semaphore Ontology Editor is a web-based application that
            manages the entire taxonomy life-cycle. From design, enhancement and enrichment to
            ongoing upkeep and maintenance, this tool provides a workbench that increases the
            productivity of information professionals through:</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Taxonomy Software</prefLabel>
        <definition>Taxonomy software provides: a user interface in which to develop a taxonomy,
            a logic layer that ensures the consistency and accuracy of the information entered,
            ideally conforming to the ISO 2788 standard 'Guidelines for the establishment and
            development of monolingual thesauri', and an application interface for other
            programs to interrogate the taxonomy as required.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Text Analytics</prefLabel>
        <definition> describes a set of linguistic, statistical, and machine learning techniques
            that break a stream of text into meaningful words or phrases in order to model and
            structure the information content of textual sources for the purposes of driving
            business intelligence, data analysis, and research.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Text Miner</prefLabel>
        <definition> makes it easy to build a taxonomy or other classification model by finding
            the most frequent terms used in your content. Text Miner searches across a set of
            documents and highlights the language you use most. It even highlights the most
            common – but pertinent – terms it finds, providing you with important context for
            those terms. It also shows you the percentage of documents that contain each term so
            that you can see how important it is to the concept that you're
            modeling.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Text Mining</prefLabel>
        <definition>Text mining is the process of deriving high-quality information from text
            using patterns and trends such as statistical pattern learning. Text mining involves
            the process of structuring the input text (usually parsing, along with the addition
            of some derived linguistic features and the removal of others, and subsequent
            insertion into a database), deriving patterns within the data, and evaluation and
            interpretation of the output. - Wikipedia</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Thesaurus</prefLabel>
        <definition>A Thesaurus is a controlled vocabulary that groups words together to provide
            definition and meaning. In Information Science this is often a structure based
            around and agreed label or Concept which than has relationships to other concepts
            such as a synonym relationship (using a "Use/Used For" or USE/UF relationship) or an
            associative relationship ("Related To" or RT/RT). The Concepts may be organized
            hierarchically, in which case this becomes and extension to a pure
            taxonomy.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Topical Website Content</prefLabel>
        <definition>All websites attempt to make their content relevant, but making it topical
            requires the integration of current stories and articles. To do this manually
            requires a high editorial resource overhead. By tagging articles against a taxonomy
            or ontology of the topics website portlets can identify and load relevant related
            content on demand.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Triple Store</prefLabel>
        <definition>A triple store or RDF store is a purpose-built database for the storage and
            retrieval of triples using semantic queries. A triple is a data entity composed of
            subject-predicate-object, such as "Bob lives in Minnesota” or "Bob likes ice-cream".
            Triple stores are optimized for the storage and retrieval of triples. In addition to
            queries, triples can usually be imported/exported using (RDF) and other
            formats.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Unstructured Data</prefLabel>
        <definition>Unstructured Data is the majority of an organization’s data which is not
            managed. Structured data is that which resides in relational or XML databases and
            can be queried. Unstructured data is the raw text content found in eMails, chat
            sessions, presentations, etc.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Variety</prefLabel>
        <definition>A defining property of which deals with the number and diverse nature of
            information in an organization. Information can be structured, semi-structured and
            unstructured. Eighty to 90% of today’s information is unstructured (i.e. emails,
            chat sessions, engineering drawings, contracts, whitepapers …) and not being used in
            decision making – can help organizations harness this valuable
            information.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Velocity</prefLabel>
        <definition>A defining property of which deals with the speed at which information is
            changing. Today organizations are dealing with large, rapidly changing volumes of
            information which they must ingest, identify and use to drive key business
            decisions. combines semantic technology with information science and allows
            organizations to analyze, describe, interpret, and visual the valuable information
            locked within their content so they can out perform their competitors.</definition>
    </concept>
    <concept>
        <prefLabel>Volume</prefLabel>
        <definition>A defining property of , which deals with the amount of data. In today’s
            marketplace the amount of data flowing into an organization is staggering. This
            information is generally unstructured and it’s increasing at an unprecedented rate.
            Organizations seek to find a way to manage the growing volumes of information to
            incorporate into decision-making processes.</definition>
    </concept>
</concepts>